You're trying a bunch of different
strategies and nothing seems to be
working. Let me break it to you. Your
strategy doesn't really matter. I've
devised a strategy called Dumb Money
Concepts. It is a play on Smart Money
Concepts. It's so incredibly simple to
follow and it's going to allow you to
focus on what actually matters in
trading. As I just said, you try a
couple different strategies, nothing
seems to be working. It's because the
strategy is not that important. This is
going to be a simple set rules that does
work for sure. Then you can focus on
your internal discipline. The problem
that most traders have when it doesn't
come to your mindset and psychology is
you're either drowning in information.
This is why I say ICT and SMC doesn't
work. This is why I say all sorts of
strategies do not work. It's because
there's so many conflicting points of
views and so many things that can mess
you up. So we must simplify it. Or two,
you have no plan whatsoever and when you
have no plan whatsoever, you don't have
targets, you don't have exits. So again,
let's make it super simple. Let's jump
into the charts. I'm going to show you
your strategy right here. Like I said,
this is the entire strategy. It's a very
quick PowerPoint, guys. You make it
super simple. You don't use any
indicators and you follow one little
thing. And all that little thing is does
it gain, does it lose a level, or does
it fail to gain or lose a level, right?
So what do I mean by that? This is the
entire strategy. We have a key point,
right? Wait for the price to hit that
level. You then have a wick or an
attempt to pass it. You have an attempt
to pass that level. You fail to. What
happens next? Boom. Close back within
the range. Next, price reverses. Where
does it reverse to for sure? It reverses
to the origin of that move, right? So
just because this continues down doesn't
necessarily mean that we're going to
trade that whole thing. We only know the
next move and we're going to simplify
that so so simple that you could have
just instantly shorted there, right?
That's it. That's literally it. So by
the end of this video, we're going to
jump into identifying levels,
determining the trend, entering and
exiting, and your risk management it
doesn't really matter cuz you're going
to be right. So
let's do it. All right, so when you're
identifying levels, let's let's start
off on the higher time frames, right?
You can use the monthly. Very often
you'll see the monthly levels here. So,
what you want to do is those untested
candle bodies. And as you can see, hey,
we have a level here. These levels are
very obviously going to be pivot points.
You know that untested monthly levels
are going to be bounced off of. It
happens for sure, okay? You just don't
know how far. So, you see there it also
lined up with a weekly and then bounced
off of it. You can also see, hey, we
have these weekly levels. So, this is
your first bet is draw out where are
these weekly and monthly levels that are
untested, okay? And then you kind of
have a range of where you're going to be
able to blindly enter on some trades,
right? And we can go back down to the
daily and you can see, hey, higher time
frames, these are going to be super
important pivot points, right? So, as we
pass this level, this is called a
pass-through level for me. We're going
to identify that level as well. And we
can identify the upper side level as
well here, right? So, we have a couple
recent levels. So, what's the difference
between a tested and an untested level?
Well, if you go back to the weekly, you
can see, hey, this level was already
tested here. And when when it tested,
you failed to go below it. So, using
this logic that we just explained at the
start, we failed to go below that level.
So, what did it do? It goes back up to
the origin of the move that brought it
down, okay? And you can see, hey, we
went right to that level before coming
back down and once again testing this
level that was then created later. We
failed to to lose it again. So, the next
move back up is going to be back up
here, okay? Back to the origin of that
move and we have to retest that level
again. Once a level has been tested
once, it's pretty unlikely that it will
hold as support unless a new level was
created there. So, you can see here,
this level tested and bounced off of
this level and this level tested and
bounced off of this level. Usually, if
you can see here, this level was already
tested and when we came up again, it
went past it and went to the next level
behind, okay? That's how we identify
important key levels. Next, we want to
determine the trend. Now, trend doesn't
really matter that much. All you really
want to know is what is the next move,
right? We can use trend to make it more
likely that our moves are going to be
correct, but the reality is, hey, if the
trend, let's call this a trend on the
higher time frame is bouncing off of
that and we say, "Hey, it's probably
going to be coming up here because we
know the next move of the weekly, then
most likely the trend on the 4-hour is
going to be following that." Okay? So,
you want to be looking for trades within
that next move. So, I'm only saying the
trend as the next higher time frame
move. I'm not identifying trend the same
way as other people do where they say
lower a higher lows and higher highs,
right? Means an uptrend. Right? We're
not doing it that way because that's a
silly way to judge it because we don't
know when it's going to turn. We know
it's going to turn up here. So, this is
the move that we're trying to satisfy on
the higher time frame trend. So, just to
be clear on that, our trends don't
really matter. What we're looking for is
the next move. And when we're looking at
the higher time frames, the next move is
a much larger move than the moves on the
lower time frames. So, everything ends
up being a fractal of each other and
they start cascading into each other.
So, the trend on the lower time frame is
going to change first and then it's
going to start cascading into the higher
time frames, thus making the higher time
frames change later. But overall, if
we're trying to find the trend and make
things most probable, we want to look at
that major move on the weekly, daily,
and monthly levels and then take trades
intraday based off of that direction.
Okay, so the next thing I want to
illustrate is we've already determined
that, hey, when we have this failure to
lose a level. We have the failure to
lose a level right here. We already know
that it's going to go back to the origin
of this move, right? We already know
that that's going to be happening,
right? Before it does comes back down.
But what happens when, you know, you get
these closes instead? These are
basically the same thing. We have a
regain of this zone. And when we regain
a zone, which is essentially the same as
having a wick because this is an attempt
to break that level and you've just
regained it really quickly. Or we can
lose the level and then regain it, okay?
So, now that we're back in this zone,
it's more confirmation that we're going
to be targeting the other side of that
zone, okay? A perfect example here is
you lost this level before and then when
you came back in and you regained it,
you gave a little wick test here of the
level before targeting the other side of
that zone. It ends up being the exact
same thing as a wick, as you can see
here. You can see the wick and then you
have target the other side of the zone.
The wick is just a more momentous move.
This all goes under the guise of what
I'm determining the trend or the next
move to be. Entering and exiting trades,
you have a few different options. We
have the option of blind entry where
it's an untested higher time frame
level, which we already talked about.
You have the option of waiting for
confirmation of a bounce off of that
level and you have the option which I
used to use in my previous lessons which
dollar cost average, which allows you to
get the best possible price without
really knowing what level it was going
to be. Each of these have their own
drawdowns and each of them have their
benefits. So let's look at it. Entering
a blind level, where you'd want to be
entering a blind level is is essentially
a untested daily, weekly, monthly, like
higher time frame untested levels. These
levels pretty much always get some sort
of reaction off of it. Let's even just
look here at like I have a blind level
right here, right? Let's look at see at
what sort of reaction that happened even
just This looked like it didn't even
bounce off of it, right? So sometimes
you won't get a reaction, but you can
literally see here there was a reaction
when it first got to that level and it
was a pretty solid reaction. So you
could have just entered blindly here
with a pretty decently tight stop and
then all you had to do was was target
the next level up. You have one hour
sort of set up here. You could have
taken quick little scalps there, but if
it did happen to dump through it, you
know, this would have been a decent
amount of drawdown that you probably
wouldn't want to hold through. So those
blind levels are best when they're used
on higher time frames and you just go
for quick scalps. Now where you'd want
to wait for a reaction would be maybe
lower time frames to see hey like I
wouldn't I probably wouldn't be looking
to blindly enter on this level here on
that four hour cuz it's a bit lower, but
I can see a reaction off that level and
we can see the wick and then from there
what you'd want to do is you'd wait for
a retest of that same level and then and
then you would get in and you would
short, right? With a stop behind
wherever and you again target the other
side. Now if you want to watch in detail
and get my exact stops, my exact take
profits, jump into the discord, jump
into in stream because I'll show you
exactly where I'm placing things. This
video is not long enough for me to tell
you all of the nuances of everything I
do because this strategy is very, very
good, okay? Like much better than what
you're going to get out of this video. I
can get like a 90% hit rate with what
I'm doing, which I can't explain in a
10-minute video. Again, everything is
always free. I will never charge you for
lessons. Nice. So, for the third option,
you can do a DCA sort of strategy. And a
DCA strategy is good if you don't really
understand what you're doing, honestly.
I don't use it as much anymore, but
sometimes if I have a zone that I'm
looking for, let's look at Bitcoin
recently here for an example, right? If
I have a zone on this higher time frame
and you it's a basically the same as a
blind entry except you have multiple
entries, right? So, you have a big zone
here. I'm going to draw like you can see
the zone on the monthly here. So, when I
entered Bitcoin, what I did is I DCA'd
at 70k and I did uh 60k because that's
the zone I wanted to enter on. So, I did
one at the top and one at the bottom.
Now, what you can do here is you can
average out as it comes back up to to
make sure you get a really good entry so
you're not over-risking. Let's break
that down in further detail just so I
can show you how you'd be exiting if
you're, you know, over-risked in a DCA.
So, in an example like this is if I I
entered here and I entered here, this is
a support that's turned resistance now.
What you'd do is you buy here and then
exit there the first trade at break
even. So, that way your first position,
you only have one position and it's
really good entry now, right? If it
continues to drop lower, you probably
would want to exit that trade because
this was your zone. I don't want you to
just keep DCA'ing as long as it's
running and Martingaling because that's
going to ruin your your account
eventually, really poor risk management.
So, as for exiting, you can either
average out the same sort of way I was
telling you here or you can simply do
the next swing high or a important key
level. So, the exact same way you're
going to enter is going to need the
exact same way you're going to exit,
okay? So, if you have major time frame
levels, right? Say I have one here, I
probably want to exit my long right
there because that's a pretty good spot
where I think price is going to reverse
at. Or I can target new highs and it's
going to be dependent on each situation,
but you're going to want to shoot for
maybe one, one and a half hour per trade
and you can justify where you want to
place it based off of that. Also, if
you're if you're entering off of a
weekly a weekly candle here, it's maybe
not a good idea to exit on a daily. You
might want to exit on the new high
because you are trading on the weekly
time frame and that might just be a
short little bounce off of it. But use
your best judgment, okay? One more thing
is if you are trading and it it tells
you that the trend has now shifted the
other way. So, let's say we were bearish
here, right? Because we had this wick on
that level, right? And we sold and we
let's say we we were targeting this low
instead of that level and they failed to
make a new a new low, now we should exit
because most likely what it's telling us
is the trend is now shifted and it's
coming back up here. So, it's a very
likely that we get stopped out of that
trade and we can just re-enter later cuz
we don't want to be attached to any
trades. We can just jump in and out, no
problem cuz we're always just looking
for what is the next move and if the
next move is going against us, we don't
want to be in that. As for risk
management, how much should you be
risking? Make sure you feel
uncomfortable while trading so that you
can practice your emotional control, but
not so uncomfortable that you have to
look at the chart. Say that again, you
want to you want to feel a little bit
uncomfort when you lose like let's say
100 bucks is a decent amount for you to
lose. I want you to bet 100 bucks then,
but I don't want you betting a thousand
dollars because then you have to look at
the chart constantly. If 100 dollars is
not a huge deal to you, but it kind of
sucks, that's the perfect amount to bet.
Stop losses, I don't really use them too
much, but the stop loss I tend to put
behind the next level behind. So, that
way your risk management, you still have
it there just in case in case something
happens, but this way it allows the
option for the market to stop out the
other guys without stopping you out. So,
if you have a level here that you want
to you want to be out at, I put my stop
loss at the next level behind instead of
that level. And then one final thing,
don't use Martingale. When I told you to
DCA, DCA once or twice, not more than
that, okay? I think that's all, boys.
Follow the live streams, join the
Discord, a lot more in detail here. I'll
review your trades, whatever you guys
want. I'm here to help, okay? Thanks for
watching.